William Van O'Connor Papers
William Van O'Connor Papers
1940-1967
O'Connor, William Van, 1915-1966.
2.0 linear ft.
Papers of the American literary critic, editor, educator, author. Collection contains correspondence (1943-1967) and writings (1960-1966). Correspondents include Kingsley Amis, Caroline Gordon, Lewis Mumford, Karl Jay Shapiro, Allen Tate, Lionel Trilling, Robert Penn Warren, and others. Writings include typescripts of books, plays, and an untitled and unfinished collection of literary reminiscences.
146329
Biographical History
William Van O'Connor (1915-1966) was an American literary critic, editor, educator, and author.
O'Connor was born in Syracuse, New York, on January 15, 1915, the son of Sarsfield and Violet Belle (McKnight) O'Connor. He attended Christian Brothers Academy and graduated from Syracuse University in 1936. After receiving an M.A. at Syracuse University in 1937, he attended Columbia University from which he earned his Ph.D. degree in 1947.
Prior to World War II, O'Connor taught at Ohio State University, 1940-1941, and at Louisiana State University, 1941-1913. A tour in the United States Army which included service in New Guinea from 1943-1946 saw him rise to the rank of Staff Sergeant. After being discharged, he taught at the University of Minnesota, 1946-1962, and at the University of California at Davis, 1962-1966, in the latter case as chairman of the English department. He received a Rockefeller Foundation fellowship, 1946-1947, acted as executive editor of American Quarterly, 1949-1951, served as Berg Professor of English and American literature at New York University, 1958, and was a Fulbright lecturer at the University of Liel, Belgium, 1953-1954, and at the University of Hull, England, 1964-1965.
O'Connor was a prolific literary critic, writer and editor. To his credit are monographs entitled New Woman of the Renaissance (with his wife), 1942; Climates of Tragedy, 1943; Sense and Sensibility in Modern Poetry, 1918; The Shaping Spirit: a Study of Wallace Stevens, 1950; An Age of Criticism, 1900-1950, 1952; The Tangled Fire of William Faulkner, 1954; Modern Prose, Form and Structure, 1958; William Faulkner, 1959; The Grotesque, An American Literary Genre, 1962; A Key to American Literature, 1962; The New University Wits, 1963; Ezra Pound, 1963; Religion and American Literature, with Robert Wiggin and Joyce Cary, 1966. O'Connor also edited Forms of Modern Fiction: Essays Collected in Honor of Joseph Warren Beach, 1948; the six volume series Twentieth Century Literature in America (with Frederick J. Hoffman), of which his own An Age of Criticism was part; a three volume History of the Arts in Minnesota, 1958; A Casebook on Ezra Pound (with Edward Stone); and Seven Modern American Novelists, 1964. He also published a book of short stories, Campus on the River, 1950, and a volume of poetry, High Meadow, 1964.
On January 23, 1942, O'Connor married Mary Theresa Allen, and the couple subsequently became the parents of two daughters, Willa Van and Ellen Lee, and a son, Jewett Marion. O'Connor died at Davis, California, on September 26, 1966, at the age of fifty-one.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The William Van O'Connor Papers consist of correspondence and writings.
Correspondence, 1943-1967, contains both incoming and outgoing. A complete index of correspondents is included at the end of this inventory.
In general, the correspondence reflects Mr. O'Connor's literary interests, although there are a number of letters of condolence to his wife following his death. Several of the British writers among his correspondents reply at length to his inquiries concerning their participation in the group called the "new university wits." A number of letters deal with the Ezra Pound controversy, and the large number of Lewis Mumford letters includes one expressing reaction to the use of the first atomic bomb. Of particular interest is the long run of letters from Karl Shapiro. Other significant correspondents include the following:
Kingsley Amis, British author, 1957-1958
Lee Anderson, 1957-1964
Joseph Warren Beach, literary critic and educator, 1946-1952
Cleanth Brooks, literary critic, 1949-1965
Erskine Caldwell, novelist, 1957
Hayden Carruth, poet, 1949
Clem Cristesen, editor of Meanjin, 1944-1947
Robert Conquest, British author, 1956, 1958
Malcolm Cowley, literary critic, 1959-1967
David Daiches, British literary critic, 1943, 1962
Donald Davie, British author, 1957-1958
T. S. Eliot, poet, 1958-1959
D. J. Enright, British author, 1958-1959
John Gould Fletcher, poet, 1943
David Garnett, British author and editor, 1954-1965
Caroline Gordon, literary critic, 1962
Thom Gunn, British author, 1958
Frederick J. Hoffman, literary critic, 1944-1966
Rolfe Humphries, poet, 1943, 1948
A. E. Johnson, poet and educator, 1914, 1958
Philip Larkin, British poet, 1958, 1964-1966
Lewis Leary, educator, 1960-1963
Harry T. Moore, literary critic and educator, 1961-1963
Lewis Mumford, author, 1944-1950
Iris Murdoch, British author, 1958
Marjorie Nicolson, educator, 1943-1963
Flannery O'Connor, author, 1947
Robert S. Phillips, 1962-1967
Katherine Anne Porter, writer, 1954
Ezra Pound, poet, 1959 (repro.)
Nat Rosen, 1949
Karl Shapiro, poet and editor, 1944-1966
Theodore Spencer, author, 1943-1945
Holly Stevens Stephenson, daughter of the poet Wallace Stevens, 1964
Wallace Stevens, poet, 1948-1951
Phil Stone, friend of William Faulkner, 1955
Allen Tate, literary critic, 1943, 1949-1962
Lionel Trilling, literary critic, 1947-1960
John Wain, British author, 1958
Robert Penn Warren, author and educator, 1944-1966
William Carlos Williams, poet, 1946, 1949
Other prominent persons represented in the correspondence by letters of lesser research significance include Louis S. Auchincloss, F. W. Bateson, Clive Bell, William Rose Benet, Eric Bentley, R. P. Blackmur, John Malcolm Brinnin, Van Wyck Brooks, Oscar Cargill, Bennett Cerf, Richard Chase, John Ciardi, Harold Clurman, Louis O. Coxe, Leon Edel, George Elliott, Francis Fergusson, Vardis Fisher, E. M. Forster, Robert B. Heilman, Irving Howe, Stanley Edgar Hyman, William Inge, Alfred Kazin, Clark Kerr, Sir Geoffrey Keynes, Joseph Wood Krutch, Stanley J. Kunitz, James Laughlin, Robert Lowell, Frederick F. Manfred, Klaus Mann, Josephine Miles, Arthur Mizener, Samuel French Morse, Wright Norris, Raymond Mortimer, Gorham Munson, Howard Nemerov, Aileen Pippett, Henry Rago, Philip Rahv, John Crowe Ransom, I. A. Richards, Mark Schorer, Allan Seeger, Wallace Stegner, E. M. N. Tillyard, William York Tindall, William Troy, Mark Van Doren, Peter Viereck, Jose Garcia Villa, Eliseo Vivas, Brom Weber, Theodore Weiss, Rene Wellek, Eudora Welty, Glenway Wescott, Oscar Williams, Leonard Woolf, and Louis Zukofsky.
Writings, 1960-1966, contain articles, books, drama, poetry and book reviews. The book category includes in several instances both a holograph and typed drafts of a work as well as galley proofs. Two of the books, Sir Ferdinando Gorges, and The Wild Swans, as well as the unfinished and untitled collection of literary reminiscences O'Connor was working on during the summer just prior to his death, are apparently unpublished. The two plays in the collection have been performed, but also apparently are unpublished. A small number of poems eliminated from the manuscript prior to publication are included in the materials relating to the poetry volume, High Meadow. The second poetry volume, Malade, a collection of verse in a lighter vein, does not appear to have been published thus far.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged chronologically, preceded by two folders of undated letters; the second of these contains those which are partially dated with a month and day but no year. Both folders of undated material are arranged alphabetically by name of sender.
Writings are subdivided by genre (drama, fiction, etc.). Each of the categories which contain more than a single item are further arranged alphabetically by title.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Fiction; Literature -- American Poetry; Amis, Kingsley.; Gordon, Caroline, 1895-1981.; Mumford, Lewis, 1895-1990.; O'Connor, William Van, 1915-1966.; Shapiro, Karl, 1913-2000.; Tate, Allen, 1899-1979.; Trilling, Lionel, 1905-1975.; Warren, Robert Penn, 1905-1989.; American literature -- 20th century.; Literature -- History and criticism.; Criticism.; Critics -- United States.; Correspondence.; Manuscripts for publication.; Authors.; Critics.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of William Van O'Connor and the William Van O'Connor Estate, 1963-1969.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - [General], 1940-1967; 26 folders (Box 1)
  - Undated, A-Z, 1940-1967 (Box 2)
- Writings
  - Articles
    - "Epigonism in Contemporary Poetry," A Comment, no. 21, Oct 1944 (Box 2)
    - "A Memory of Theodore Roethke," Critical Quarterly, 1965 (Box 2)
    - "Parody as Criticism," College English (Box 2)
    - "A Tribute to Joseph Warren beach," Poetry, XLI, 192-194, Dec 1957 (Box 2)
  - Books
    - An Age of Criticism, 1900-1950, 1952 (Box 2)
    - Ezra Pound, 1963 (Box 2)
    - The Grotesque, An American Literary Genre, circa 1962
      - Manuscript, pages 1-327, 3 folders (Box 2)
      - Galley proofs (Box 2)
    - Joyce Cary, 1966
      - Draft A, holograph, 1964-1965 (Box 2)
      - Draft B, typescript revised, 1964-1969 (Box 2)
      - Galley proof A, revised (Box 2)
      - Galley proof B, revised (Box 2)
    - The New University Wits, circa 1963
      - Draft A, typescript copy (Box 3)
      - Draft B, typescript revised, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Page proofs (Box 3)
    - Sir Ferdinando Gorges, Founder of American Colonies, Summer 1964; holograph and typescript revised (Box 3)
    - The Wild Swans, alternate title: The Swans of Shelley Lake
      - Draft A, typescript copy and holograph revised (Box 3)
      - Draft B, typescript revised, chapters 1-23; 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Draft B, typescript revised, chapters 24-42 (Box 4)
    - Untitled literary reminiscences, Summer 1966 (Box 4)
  - Drama
    - "The Heron and the Hawk", circa 1963; typescript and typescript revised (Box 4)
    - "In the Cage", 1960-1961; typescript and printed material (Box 4)
    - "In the Cage", 1960-1961; notes (Box 4)
  - Fiction
    - "Durham Woods," short story, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Poetry
    - High Meadow, 1964
      - Typescript, typescript revised, reproduction revised, and holograph (Box 4)
      - Poems not used, typescript, typescript revised, repro. revised (Box 4)
      - Page proofs (Box 4)
    - Malade: Twenty-One Poems on the Same Theme, undated (Box 4)
  - Reviews
    - Ehrengard, by Isak Dinesen, New York Times Book Review, Jun 9, 1963 (Box 4)
    - No In Thunder, by Leslie Fiedler, Saturday Review, Nov 19, 1960 (Box 4)
    - Untitled review of seven books, Southern Review, circa 1965 (Box 4)
  - Fragments
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
Selected Index to Correspondence
Acevedo, Cristobal de 1962 Feb 5 1962 Mar 16 1962 Sep 10
Acevedo, Cristobal de 1962 Feb 5 1962 Mar 16 1962 Sep 10
American Oxonian 1947 Mar 13 (Denham Sutcliffe)
Amis, Kingsley, 1922- 1957 Nov 9 1958 Jan 6 1958 Jan 21 1958 Aug 22
Anciaux, Andree 1954 Jan 28
Anderson, Howard P. 1962 Aug 23
Anderson, Lee 1957 Sep 10 1957 Sep 15 1957 Oct 16 1961 Feb 5 1963 undated (2 items) 1963 Jan 3 1963 May 14 1963 Jul 2 1963 Aug 17 1963 Sep 5 1963 Oct 6 1963 Oct 11 1963 Oct 20 1963 Oct 27 1963 Nov 14 1964 Apr 9
Applegate, Howard L. see Syracuse University
Auchincloss, Louis Stanton 1963 1963 Apr 17
Baker, Howard 1963 Apr 16
Balon, B. 1962 Feb 8 1962 Sep 22
Barnes & Noble, Inc. 1962 Apr 26 (John D. Wieboldt) 1963 Feb 14 ( " ) 1963 Feb 19 (Dick Epler)
Bateson, Frederick Wilse, 1901- 1963 Jul 18
Beach, Joseph Warren, 1980- undated 1946 Aug 31 telegram 1946 Sep 5 1948 Dec 3 1949 Jan 14 1952 Oct 16 1952 Nov 1
Beck, Warren 1959 Jun 30
Bell, Clive, 1881- 1954 Jul 9
Benet, William Rose, 1886-1950 1948 Jul 16 1948 Jul 26 (Anne G. Mulcahy, Secy)
Bentley, Eric Russell, 1916- undated 1948 Jul 16 1958 Feb 16 1960 Dec 28 1961 Apr 18 1961 Jun 8
Blackmur, Richard Palmer, 1904-1965 1959 Feb 18 1959 May 6 1959 May 13 1959 Oct 29
Bowron, Barney and Lucy 1966 Sep 27 telegram
Bradbury, Malcolm 1965 Jan 18 1965 Jun 8 1966 Jul 14
Brennan, Dan 1960 Feb 1
Brinnin, John Malcolm, 1916- 1959 Aug 8
Brooks, Cleanth, 1906- undated 1949 Aug 19 1962 Nov 16 1962 Nov 25 1963 ? 1963 Sep 26 1961 Dec 9 1965 Jan 7 1965 Feb 25 1965 Jul 21 1965 Oct 26
Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886- 1948 Jul 23
Brown, Francis 1948 Sep 17
CBS Television Network 1959 Dec 30 (Larry White)
Caldwell, Erskine, 1903- 1957 Feb 3
Campbell, Oscar James 1945 Aug 23
Cargill, Oscar, 1898- 1960 Jun 2
Carpenter, Nan C. 1960 Nov 17
Carruth, Hayden, 1921- 1949 Apr 6 1949 Jun 20
Cerf, Bennett Alfred, 1898- 1949 Jul 15
Chase, Richard 1961 May 5 1962 May 5
Christesen, Clem 1944 Dec 7 1944 Dec 29 1945 May 21 1945 Aug 8 1945 Oct 5 (2 letters) 1946 Aug 21 1947 Jan 10
Ciardi, John, 1916- 1961 Aug 4 1961 Sep 19 1961 Dec 13
Clemens, Cyril see International Mark Twain Society
Clurman, Harold 1961 Apr 11
Columbia University 1947 May 28
Conquest, Robert 1956 May 19 1958 Apr 3 1958 May 12 1958 Jun 28 1958 Aug 28
Couch, W. T. see University of Chicago Press
Cowley, Malcolm, 1898- 1959 Dec 23 1960 Jan 18 1960 Aug 18 1960 Dec 19 1961 Jan 7 1961 Apr 14 1961 May 9 1962 Mar 22 (2 letters) 1962 Oct 8 1962 Oct 21 1962 Dec 28 1963 Jan 23 1963 Feb 4 1963 Mar 31 1963 Oct 20 1966 Feb 22 1966 Jun 8 1967 Jan 6
Coxe, Louis Osborne, 1918- 1961 May 29
Curtis Brown Ltd. 1965 Jun 17 (Richard Simon)
Daiches, David, 1912- 1943 Aug 27 1943 Nov 8 1962 Mar 7
Daly, John Charles Jr., 1914- 1959 Apr 24
Davie, Donald Alfred, 1922- 1957 Dec 31 1958 Aug 30
Dempsey, David 1949 Dec 29
Downer, Alan Seymour, 1912- 1944 Feb 23
Dudley, Ed 1966 Dec 24
Edell Leon, 1907- 1959 Mar 20
Eliot, Thomas Stearns, 1888-1965 1958 Dec 5 (Ann Macfadyen, Secy) 1958 Dec 19 1959 Jan 9
Ellegood, Donald R. 1963 Feb 18
Elliott, George P. 1964 Dec 6
Encyclopaedia Britannica 1957 Mar 20 (Walter Yust)
Engle, Pantella 1966 Sep 29
Enright, Dennis Joseph, 1920- 1958 May 8 1958 Jun 16 1958 Sep 16 1959 Feb 11
Epler, Dick see Barnes & Noble, Inc.
Erskine, Albert undated (autographed card)
Ervin, John, Jr. 1958 Jan 23 1964 Aug 5 1966 May 25 1966 Sep 26
Espinosa, J. Manuel 1953 Jun 17
Feldheim, Marvin 1947 Jan 9
Feikema, Feike see Manfred, Frederick Feikema
Ferguson (J. G.) and Associates 1962 Dec 17 (T. C. Jones)
Fergusson, Francis, 1904- 1958 Oct 10 1962 Feb 1 1962 Oct 2
Fisher, Vardis, 1895- 1960 Jul 29
Fishman, Sol & Charlyn 1966 Sep 28
Fletcher, John Gould, 1886-1950 1943 Oct 9
Forster, Edward Morgan, 1879- 1954 Jul 17 1954 Jul 18
Garnett, David, 1892- undated 1954 Jun 25 1954 Jul 19 1956 Sep 5 1959 Oct 19 1959 Nov 12 1960 Mar 8 1962 Nov 21 1962 Dec 29 1964 Apr 20 1964 May 25 1964 Sep 19 1964 Dec 24 1965 Jan 22 1965 Jan 29 1965 Feb 6 1965 Feb 20 1965 Jun 6 1965 Aug 13 1965 Aug 30
Gerard, Albert 1963 Jul 16 1966 Oct 7 1967 Jan 10
Gilmour, Ian 1958 Apr 24
Gordon, Caroline, 1895- 1962 May 23 undated (Saturday) undated (5 letters)
Gunn, Thom, 1929- 1958 Mar 29 1958 Aug 18 1964 Apr 1
Halio, Jay 1967 Jan
Hall, Varian F. see Crowell, (Thomas Y.) Co.
Hancock, Henry and Betty 1966 Sep 29
Harper's Magazine 1962 Nov 15
Hart, William B. 1960 Feb 5
Hatfield, W. Wilbur 1948 Sep 16
Hawes, John T. 1960 Jan 11 1966 Sep 30
Heilman, Robert Bechtold, 1906- 194-Jun 11 194-Nov 3 194-Nov 23 1945 Jan 15
Helmbold, William undatedMar 14 1967 Jan 10
Hessler, Margery 1966 Oct?
Hillhouse, Mildred (Mrs. James T.) 1966 Sep 27
Hirsh, Edgar Lewis 1947 Feb 22
Hirsh, Margaret (Mrs. Edgar Lewis) 1966 Sep 27
Hoffman, Frederick J. 1944 Apr 17 1944 Jul 12 1944 Oct 23 1944 Dec 18 1945 Jul 30 1945 Aug 18 1945 Sep 13 1946 Sep 3 1946 Dec 7 1961 Nov 16 1962 Nov 27 1966 Oct 7
Holloway, John 1958 Apr 23
Horneburger, Theodore 1966 Oct?
Hoopes, Robert 1958 May 21
Horizon Press 1963 Jan 18 (Ben Raeburn) 1963 Jan 23 ( " ) 1963 Feb 15 ( " )
Hoskins, Frank L., Jr. 1963 Jan 4 1963 Mar 17
Howe, Irving, 1920- 1952 Oct 13
Humphries, Rolfe, 1891- 1943 Nov? 1943 Nov 11
Thanksgiving Day 1948 Sep 28
Hughes, Glenn 1962 Sep 11
Hurrell, Dennis 1966 Oct 30
Hyman, Stanley Edgar, 1919- 1961 Apr 22
Indiana University Press 1958 Nov 26
Inge, Villiam Motter, 1913- 1963 Sep 17
International Mark Twain Society 1950 Jun 1 (Cyril Clemens)
Jeffares, A. Norman 1965 Dec 13
Johnson, A. E. 1944 Jun 26 1944 Jul 15 (2 copies, 1 annot.) 1958 Jan 31
Johnson, Catherine (Mrs. A.E.) 1960 Dec 1
Jones, Brynmor 1966 Oct 7
Jones, Joseph 1964 Dec 9
Kwiat, Joseph and Charlotte 1962 Nov 22 1966 Sep 26
Langford, Richard E. 1964 ? 1964 Feb 19 1964 Apr 1 1964 Apr 14
Larkin, Philip, 1922- 1958 Apr 2 1958 Apr 11 1958 Apr 24 1958 Aug 22 1964 Mar 1964 Mar 24 1964 Apr 23 1964 May 26 1965 Jun 23 1965 Sep 8 1966 Dec 20
Laughlin, James 1949 Nov 23 1965 Sep 3
Jones, T. C. see Ferguson (J. G.) and Associates
Judge, Joan F. 1963 Feb 13
Kazin, Alfred, 1915- undatedApr 17
Kerr, Clark, 1911- 1963 Mar 5 1964 Feb 7 1966 Sep 28
Keynes, Sir Geoffrey, 1887- 1956 Oct 7
Keithy, Robert 1965 Aug 1
Kohler, Charlotte see Virginia Quarterly Review
Krieger, Murray 1956 Oct 24
Krutch, Joseph 'Mood, 1893- 1948 Jun 20
Kunitz, Stanley Jasspon, 1905- 1952 Oct 29 1963 Mar 13 telegram
Kwist, Joseph and Charlotte 1962 Nov 22 1966 Sep 26
Langford, Richard E. 1964 ? 1964 Feb 19 1964 Apr 1 1964 Apr 14
Larkin, Philip, 1922- 1958 Apr 2 1958 Apr 11 1958 Apr 24 1958 Aug 22 1964 Mar 1964 Mar 24 1964 Apr 23 1964 May 26 1965 Jun 23 1965 Sep 8 1966 Dec 20
Laughlin, James 1949 Nov 23 1965 Sep 3
Lea, Thomas C. 1949 Feb 10
Leary, Lewis, 1906- 1960 Mar 26 1960 May 12 1960 Dec 31 1962 May 21 1962 Jul 27 1962 Aug 28 1962 Oct 3 1963 Mar 19 1966 Sep 29
Letarges, Josh 1966 Sep 27
Levinson, Jack 1966 Sep 26
Lippincott, Ben 1966 Sep 28 telegram
Lippincott, Gertrude 1966 Oct?
Louisiana State University Press 1964 Jun 3 (Richard L. Wentworth)
Lowell, Robert, 1917- 1961 Jan 2
Lowry, W. McNeil 1960 Mar 9
Lytle, Andrew Nelson, 1902- 1963 Jun 11
McCoy, William F. 1966 Sep 26
Macleod, Norman 1945 Jul 4
Manfred, Frederick Feikema, 1912- 1948 Oct 23 1949 Jan 11 1957 Jul 17
Mann, Klaus, 1906-1949 1943 Nov 11 1943 Dec 12
Meserole, Harrison T. 1966 Oct 5
Miles, Josephine, 1911- 196- 1961 Dec 5 1963 May 27
Mizener, Arthur Moore, 1907- 1959 Oct 26
Moore, Geoffrey Herbert, 1920- 1957 Jan 6 1964 May 26 1964 May 29 1966 Oct 7
Moore, Harry Thornton, 1908- 1961 Sep 8 1961 Oct 14 1961 Oct 22 1961 Dec 6 1962 May 30 1962 Dec 5 1963 1963 Jul 22 1963 Oct 25 1963 Dec 3
Mooser, Gurden 1966 Dec 15
Morse, Samuel French 1957 May 7 1960 Aug 8 1960 Sep 30
Morris, Wright, 1910- 196-May 14
Mortimer, Raymond, 1895- 1954 Jul 23 1955 Feb 15
Moss, Howard 1954 Dec 6
Mrak, Emil M. 1963 Jun 3 1966 Oct 5
Mumford, Lewis, 1895- 1944 Sep 10 1944 Oct 15 1945 Jan 1 1945 Feb 22 1945 Mar 11 1945 Jun 1 1945 Jul 22 1945 Aug 19 1945 Nov 3 1946 Jan 6 1946 Dec 30 1947 Jan 8 1947 Jul 6 1948 Jul 23 1949 Jan 9 1949 Oct 10 1950 Jan 1
Munson, Gorham Bert, 1896- 1946 Jul 12 1966 Nov 30
Murdoch, Iris, 1919- undated (circa 1958) 1958 ?Feb 7
Musgrove, S. 1953 Nov 18
Nemerov, Howard, 1920- 1959 Jun 4 1959 Jul 6
Nicolson, Marjorie Hope, 1894- 1943 Nov 1 1943 Nov 17 1946 Mar 2? 1947 Mar 3 1947 Mar 10 1947 Jul 28 1947 Oct 22 1954 Oct 11 1957 Jul 24 1963 Jul 30
Oates, Joyce Carol 1963 Aug 6
O'Connor, Flannery, 1925- 1957 Jan 19
Pattinson, William 1966 Nov 25
Phillips, Robert S. 1962 Aug 29 1962 Sep 16 1962 Dec 26 1963 Feb 19 1963 Jul 18 1963 Aug 7 1963 Oct 27 1965 Jun 10 1965 Aug 22 1966 Jun 3 1966 Aug 11 1967 Feb 14
Pinto, Vivian de Sole, 1895- 1965 Mar 19 1965 Jul 3 1965 Dec 25 1966 Jul 30 1966 Sep 27 telegram 1966 Sep 27 1966 Oct 13
Pippett, Aileen (Mrs. Roger) 1956 Sep 20 1956 Oct 11 1956 Oct 30
Porter, Katherine Anne, 1894- 1954 Apr 2? 1954 May 14 1954 May 22, incl. photo
Pound, Ezra, 1885- 1959 Jun 15, reproduction
Powers, Jim undated
Princeton University Press see Smith, Datus C. Jr.
Pryce-Jones, Alan see Times Literary Supplement
Puknat, Betty (Mrs. Siegfried B.) 1966 Oct?
Puknat, Siegfried B. 1966 Oct 2
Putney, Wright Westcott 194-3 letters 1944 Aug 3
Raeburn, Ben see Horizon Press
Rago, Henry Anthony, 1915- 1957 Aug 28
Rahv, Philip, 1908- 1958 Nov 22 1960 Sep 28 1960 Dec 13
Ramsay, Robert L. 1946 Nov 16
Ransom, John Craxe, 1888- 195-Feb 14 1956 Dec 3 1957 Aug 14 1957 Sep 37 [27] 1959 Feb 14
Read, Sir Herbert Edward, 1893- 1965 Dec 13
Reisman, Leon 1966 Sep 30
Richards, Ivor Armstrong, 1893- 1944 Jan 10
Roethke, Beatrice (Mrs. Theodore) 1963 Feb 16 1965 Feb 7
Rosen, Nat 1949 Aug 26
Ruben, Louis 1961 Mar 21
Russell, Robert E. 1966 Sep 26
Schorer, Mark, 1908- 1960 Apr 30 1961 Nov 7 1963 Apr 23 1963 Aug 6 1964 Mar 27 1965 May 12
Seager, Allan, 1906- 1959 May 20
Shannon, James P. (auxiliary bishop of St. Paul) 1966 Sep
Shapiro, Karl, 1913- undated no year Jun 2 no year Jul 1 no year Jul 31 no year Aug 20 no year Aug 23 1944 Sep 9 1944 Sep 22 1944 Oct 1 1944 Oct 11 1944 Oct 12 1944 Nov 3 1944 Nov 12 1944 Nov 25 1944 Dec 10 1944 Dec 19 1944 Dec 25 1945 Apr 30 1945 Aug 11 1945 Aug 22 1945 Sep 24 1945 Nov 6 1945 Nov 23 1946 Jan 24 1946 Jan 27 1946 Feb 25 1946 Mar 6 1946 Mar 23 1946 Apr 9 1946 Apr 30 1946 May 24 1946 Jun 6 1946 Jul 10 1946 Jul 25 1946 Aug 24 1946 Sep 14 1947 Jan 27 1947 Mar 5 1947 Mar 17 1947 Apr 11 1947 May 22 1947 Jul 17 1947 Aug 8 1947 Sep 19 1947 Oct 3 1947 Dec 10 1948 Feb 25 1948 May 15 1948 Oct 20 1948 Nov 3 1949 Jan 11 1949 Jan 17 1949 Mar 31 1949 Apr 11 1949 May 31 1949 Jul 25 1949 Nov 8 1949 Nov 27 1950 or 1951 Apr 20 1950 or 1951 Sep 20 1950 Jan 3 1950 Jan 11 1950 Feb 21 1950 Mar 24 1950 Apr 27 1950 Jun 8 1950 Aug 7 1950 Aug 8 1950 Aug 18 1950 Oct 18 1951 Jan 3 1951 Apr 23 1951 May 17 1951 May 31 1951 Jul 3 1951 Jul 30 1951 Aug 1 1951 Aug 21 1951 Sep 4 1951 Sep 13 1951 Sep 24 1951 Nov 13 1951 Nov 26 1951 Dec 12 1952 Jul 15 1952 Oct 8 1953 Jun 15 1953 Dec 9 1954 Sep 21 1954 Sep 30 1954 Oct 13 1954 Oct 25 1954 Nov 1 1954 Nov 8 1954 Nov 13 1954 Nov 24 1955 Oct 17 1955 Oct 25 1955 Nov 12 1955 Nov 15 1955 Nov 17 1955 Nov 28 1956 Feb 11 1956 Oct 23 1956 Nov 7 1956 Dec 21 1957 Mar 28 1957 Apr 26 1957 Sep 27 1957 Nov 21 1957-1962 1958-1962 Jun 22 1958-1962 Tuesday 1958 Jan 31 1958 May 26 1958 Sep 30 1959 Feb 19 1959 Apr 20 1959 Apr 28 1959 May 4 1959 May 7 1959 May 12 1959 May 18 1959 Jun 10 1959 Jun 15 1959 Jul 1 1959 Jul 6 1959 Jul 13 1959 Jul 16 1959 Oct 5 1959 Oct 26 1959 Nov 21 1960 Mar 12 1960 Mar 21 1960 Aug 31 1961 Apr 11 1961 May 4 1961 May 22 1961 Jun 16 1961 Jun 19 1961 Sep 9 1961 Oct 29 1962 Oct 30 1963 Jul 23 1966 Jan 6
Simon, Irene 1966 Sep 28
Simon, Richard see Curtis Brown Ltd.
Smith, Datus C., Jr. 1948 Apr 15
Southern Illinois University Press 1962 May 31 (Vernon Steinberg) 1962 Jun 13 ( " ) 1962 Jul 26 ( " ) 1962 Nov 21 ( " ) 1963 Jan 21 ( " ) 1963 Jan 30 ( " ) 1963 Feb 8 ( " ) 1963 Feb 26 ( " ) 1963 Mar 7 ( " ) 1963 Mar 25 ( " )
Southern Review 1964 Jul 14
Spencer, Theodore, 1902-1949 1943 Dec 14 1945 Jun 26 1945 Aug 23
Stanley, Donald undatedMar 8 1963 Aug 21
Stegner, Wallace Earle, 1909- 1965 Dec 19
Steinberg, Vernon see Southern Illinois University Press
Stephenson, Holly Stevens 1964 Jun 20 1964 Jul 26 1964 Aug 25 1964 Sep 17
Stevens, Wallace, 1879- 1948 Apr 9 1948 May 14 1948 May 19 1948 May 24 1948 May 25 1948 Jul 22 1948 Sep 24 1949 Mar 25 1949 Mar 28 1949 Mar 31 1949 Nov 17 1949 Dec 28 1950 Apr 25 1951 Aug 13
Stone, Phil 1955 Nov 15
Strauss, Helen see William Morris Agency
Sutcliffe, Denham see American Oxonian
Syracuse University 1963 Mar 11 (Howard L. Applegate) 1965 Sep 16 ( " )
Tannenbaum, Lawrence 1947 Jan 14